Colleagues, the president has made clear, as I have in this council, that we stand unequivocally for the protection of civilian life during conflict.
Will those in favor of the draft resolution please raise their hand?
Will those against?
The draft resolution has not been adopted owing to the negative vote of a permanent member of the council.
So that was Linda Thomas-Greenfield, the U.S. ambassador to the U.N., and she raised her hand and voted against the Brazilian resolution to create a humanitarian corridor and bring humanitarian pauses to Gaza so that they can get food, supplies, medicine, etc., and also possibly a way out.
The resolution required the U.S. to vote in order for it to get the number of votes needed for it to pass.
So they effectively, singularly, prevented it.
She voted against this because it didn't say that Israel has a right to defend itself in the resolution.
Russia offered amendments that were struck down and not accepted by the U.K. and America.
Now, according to reporting, what it did say was that it is a ceasefire on all civilians.
She also went on to say that really they're just jumping to conclusions that they need to allow time for Joe Biden to talk his talk with Netanyahu.
This is just simply a glaring act of lack of humanitarian thought, courage, compassion by American leadership.
And, you know, the other countries have voiced very clearly that they are not here for this and that they see America.
And they demonstrated this by turning their backs on them, literally in the chamber.
Which is exactly what America and the U.K. are doing to Palestinians and to Israelis, because if you are not allowing there to be humanitarian relief for these people, you are inciting more violence for the future.
Thank you.